以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以我们真的在进行这次审查
so we're really moving along this review
线性代数和。的亮点
of highlights of linear algebra and
今天它的矩阵问他们得到了这个名字
today it's matrices Q they get that name
在那里，他们有正交列等等
there they have orthonormal columns so
这是一个人的样子，然后是
that's what one looks like and then the
关键事实正交列翻译
key fact orthonormal columns translates
直接进入你这个简单的事实
directly into that simple fact that you
每次看到都要记住
just keep remembering every time you see
Q转置Q你有自己的身份
Q transpose Q you've got the identity
矩阵让我们看看为什么Q转置
matrix let's just see why so Q transpose
我会把那些专栏和
would be I'll take those columns and
把它们分成几行，然后我成倍增加
make them into rows and then I multiply
通过Q与列，我得到了什么
by Q with the columns and what do I get
也希望我得到的单位矩阵
well hopefully I get the identity matrix
好的
okay
为什么因为哦是的正常部分
why because oh yeah the normal part
告诉我每个载体的长度
tells me that the lengths of each vector
这就是长度平方Q转置Q.
that's the length squared Q transpose Q
长度的平方是1，所以给了我
the length squared is 1 so that gives me
沿着身份矩阵中的1
the 1 in the identity matrix along the
对角然后Q转置时间a
diagonal and then Q transpose times a
不同的Q是0，这是正交部分
different Q is 0 that's the ortho part
所以这给了我零，所以这是一个
so that gives me the zeros so that's a
简单的身份，但它翻译成一个
simple identity but it translates from a
很多单词变成了简单的表达
lot of words into a simple expression
现在这意味着在另一个
now does that mean that in the other
订购QQ转置就是那个身份
order Q Q transpose is that the identity
这使对想到一个问题
that's so that's a question to think
关于QQ转置等于身份
about is QQ transpose equal the identity
题
question
有时是有时候不容易说出来
sometimes yes sometimes no easy to tell
答案是肯定的，当Q是
which the answer is yes yes when Q is
如果Q是a，则答案是肯定的
square the answer is yes if Q is a
方阵矩阵这是方阵
square matrix a square matrix a this is
说方阵Q有这个
saying that the square matrix Q has that
左边是倒数，但是是正方形
inverse on its left but for square
矩阵左逆Q转置是
matrices a left inverse Q transpose is
对于正方形也是正确的反转
also a right inverse so for a square
矩阵如果你有工作的逆
matrix if you have an inverse that works
一方面它将在另一方面工作
on one side it will work on the other
那边答案是肯定的
side so the answer is yes in that case
然后在那种情况下就是这种情况
and then in that case that's the case
当我们打电话给Q时我们真的没有
when we call Q is well we really don't
知道正确的名字是什么但是
know what the right name would be but
这是每个人都使用的名字
here's the name everybody uses an
正交矩阵，这是唯一的
orthogonal matrix and that's that's only
在他们的方形案例广场这里是一个
in their square case square here is an
正交矩阵右边你-
orthogonal matrix right right do you -
你想看一个例子吗？
do you want to just see an example of
如何工作，如果Q，它将不会如此
how that works and it will not so if Q
是矩形让我做一个
is rectangular let's let me do a
矩形Q和方形Q好方形
rectangular Q and square Q okay square
没事高兴看到一些正交
all right good to see some orthogonal
矩阵，因为我的信息就是这样
matrices because my message is that
它们在各种方面都非常重要
they're really important in all kinds of
应用程序让我从2开始
applications let's start two-by-two I
可以想到两种不同的方式
can think of two different ways to get
一个2乘2的正交矩阵
an orthogonal matrix that's a 2 by 2
矩阵，其中一个你会知道
matrix and one of them you will know
马上就是thethesinetheta所以
immediately cos theta sine theta so
这是一个单位向量，它是标准化的cos
that's a unit vector it's normalized cos
平方加正弦平方是1和这个
squared plus sine squared is 1 and this
人必须是垂直于它
guy has to be orthogonal to it
所以我做了-正弦theta和cos
so I make that - sine theta and cos
theta没关系
theta okay
那些都是他们的链接
those are both links one they're
正交然后这是我的Q和
orthogonal then this is my Q and the
如果我，Q的倒数将是转置
inverse of Q will be the transpose if I
乘以转置会把
multiply the transpose would put the
减号在这里生产
minus sign down here and would produce
逆矩阵是什么
the inverse matrix and what is that
特定的矩阵表示为什么这样做
particular matrix represent whoa why do
从几何上看，为什么我们在哪里看到
geometrically why do we where do we see
这个矩阵是轮换的，谢谢你
that matrix it's a rotation thank you
这是整个飞机的旋转
it's a rotation of the whole plane by
SATA
是的，如果我将其应用于零
yeah so so if I apply that to one zero
例如，我得到第一列
for example I get the first column which
是因为thetasinetheta，那就是
is cos theta sine theta and that's just
一根绳子让我画出一幅矢量图片
a rope let me draw a picture that vector
10已经向上旋转-所以有
1 0 has got rotated up - so there's the
10在那里它旋转了
the 1 0 and there it got rotated through
角度θ和类似的01将
an angle theta and similarly 0 1 will
旋转角度θ2
get rotated through an angle theta 2
那么整架飞机都旋转哦
there so the whole plane rotates oh that
让我记住一个非常重要的事情
makes me remember a highly important
Q的一个非常重要的属性它没有
very important property of Q it doesn't
改变长度任何向量的长度
change length the length of any vector
旋转后它是一样的
is the same after you rotate it the
任何矢量的长度都是相同的
length of any vector is the same after
你乘以Q我可以做到这一点
you multiply by Q can I just do that
我声称任何X想要的任何X
I claim any X any vector X I want to
看看QX的长度，我声称
look at the length of Q X and I claim
它与X的长度相同
that it has the same length as X
实际上这就是原因
actually that's the reason in
正交矩阵的计算
computations that orthogonal matrix are
如此受欢迎，因为没有溢出可以
so much loved because no overflow can
发生在正交矩阵长度上
happen with orthogonal matrices lengths
不要改变我可以乘以任何
don't change I can multiply by any
正交矩阵的数量和
number of orthogonal matrices and the
长度不变，我们可以看到原因
lengths don't change can we just see why
那是真的你怎么样我们呢？
that's true how would you so what do we
必须继续我们
have to go on we
我们要做的是Q转置Q.
what we have to go on is Q transpose Q
等我每当我们要证明它的时候
equal I whenever we're gonna prove it's
得出来的，由于这是
got to come out of that because that's
所有我们都知道，所以如何使用它来获得
all we know so how do I use that to get
那
that
好吧，我们还没有说很多
well we haven't said a whole lot about
长度，但你现在看到的这一切，它会
lengths but you'll see it all now it'll
更容易证明正方形
be easier to prove that the squares are
同样如此，什么是矩阵
the same so what's the what's the matrix
表达式的长度平方是什么的
expression for the length squared what's
什么是右边的那一面
what's the right-hand side of that
等式X转置X右X转置
equation X transpose X right X transpose
X给出了正方形的总和
X gives me the sum of the squares
毕达哥拉斯说这是长度
Pythagoras says that's the length
平方，使右手边是X.
squared so that right hand side is X
转置X什么是左侧
transpose X what's the left side
这是QX的长度平方所以
it's a length squared of this of QX so
它必须与hueX转置相同
it must be the same as hue X transpose
QX和声称是那个等式
QX and the claim is that that equation
抱着，你看到了吗？
holds and do you see it
如果来自Q，那么任何财产都在哪里
whereís so any property if from Q is
将有干脆直接走出来
going to has to just come out directly
从那里我只是在这里
from that where is it here do I just
喜欢在那个左边推开一点点
like push away a little bit at that left
手边看到它
hand side and see it
QX转置与X转置相同
QX transpose is the same as X transpose
Q转置和QX是QX，现在我
Q transpose and QX is QX and now I'm
眼看还有你可能会说等一下
seeing well you might say wait a minute
括号在那里，但在那里
the parentheses were there and there but
我说矩阵最重要的法则
I say the most important law for matrix
乘法是你可以移动
multiplication is you can move
括号或扔掉它们让我们
parentheses or throw them away let's
在这里漫游所以我在看Q
roam away so in here I'm seeing Q
转置Q这是什么身份
transpose Q which is the identity so
这是这是真的耶，这样意味着，
it's it's true yeah so that means that
你永远不会下溢或溢出
you're never underflow or overflow when
你将每个数字乘以Q.
you're multiplying by Q every numerical
算法编写使用正交
algorithm is written to use orthogonal
矩阵，如果可以的话，可以和
matrices if wherever it can can okay and
这是第一个例子
here's the first example
我想对我来说可能有好处
I think maybe good for me to think of
其他例子或我们想到的
other examples or for us to think of
正交矩阵的其他例子也是如此
other examples of orthogonal matrices so
我正在使用那个词正交矩阵I.
I'm using that word orthogonal matrix I
应该真的应该真的
should it really should we should really
说正统，我真的
be saying orthonormal and I'm really
主要考虑方形的，所以
thinking mostly of square ones so so the
所以在Q转置时的方形情况下
so in the square case when Q transpose
当然Q逆这一事实使得
is Q inverse of course that fact makes
很容易地解决都方程
it easy to solve all equations that have
Q因为你是一个系数矩阵
Q as a coefficient matrix because you
想要逆，你只需要使用
want the inverse and you just use the
转置好吧让我们来看看吧
transpose okay let's just take a some
几分钟想起Q的，如果实例
minutes to think of examples of Q's if
它们必须如此重要
they're so important there have to be
有趣的例子，那是一个
interesting examples and that was a
第一个现在还有一个
first one now there's one more
我是你的两个二个例子
two-by-two example that I that you
应该知道你知道那会是什么
should know do you know what that would
是
be
所以另一个这将是例子二和
so another this will be example two and
它也将只有两个两个
it's also going to be only two by two
真实的，我有什么可能性
and real and what possibility have I got
离开这里我将使用相同的第一列
left here I'll use the same first column
costhetasinetheta因为那更多
cos theta sine theta because that's more
或者更少的任何单位向量
or less any any unit vector in two
尺寸已经形成了这种形式
dimensions this has got that form so
你对第二个提出了什么建议？
what do you propose for the second
柱
column
是的是把减号放下来
yes yeah put the put the minus sign down
在这里，你认为这样做
here so you think does that make any
差异所以正弦θ和负cos
difference so sine theta and minus cos
theta我不知道你是否曾经看过
theta I don't know if you've ever looked
在那个矩阵你知道我们正在努力
at that matrix you know we're trying to
收集在一起几个矩阵
collect together a few matrices that are
值得了解的是值得看的好
worth knowing are worth looking at okay
现在发生了什么样的事情
now what kind of what's happened here
你可能会说这是一个微不足道的变化
you may say that was a trivial change
它有点像但它是一个
which it kind of was but it's a
不同的矩阵现在不是轮换
different matrix now it's not a rotation
再
anymore
那不是死记硬背
that's not a rote
是的，现在它是对称的
and yeah somehow now it's symmetric and
[音乐]
[Music]
是的，它的特征向量必须是什么
yeah what its eigenvectors must be
某些东西或其他我们会得到那些
something or other we'll get to those
但是那个矩阵做了什么呢？
but what did what does that matrix do I
不知道我不知道你是否见过
don't know I don't know if you've seen
它，如果你没有它不是它没有
it if you haven't it's not it doesn't
跳出但它是一个重要的情况下，该
jump out but it's a important case this
它是一个反射矩阵通知
is a reflection matrix notice that it's
确定它是负1你有减去
determined it is minus 1 you have minus
cos平方θ减去正弦平方
cos squared theta minus sine squared
theta确定的是-1
theta it's determinate is minus 1
它有一些特征值
there's some some some eigenvalue it
得出那个有-是的
coming up with that that's got a - yeah
好的，我的意思是反思
ok so what do I mean by a reflection
矩阵让我画飞机，我想
matrix let me draw the plane and I think
所以10让我们再跟着它1
so so 1 0 let's follow it follow again 1
0去哪儿了
0 where does that go
这给了我第一列
that gives me the first column so as
在它去costheta正弦theta之前
before it goes to cos theta sine theta
当我说反思让我放
and when I say reflection let me put put
镜子进入图片所以你
the the mirror into the picture so you
看看镜子的反射是什么
see what reflection it is the mirror is
在这里角度命运/-留下来
is along here at angle fate / - stayed
过度生活，确保足够的角度
over to live so sure enough 1 0 at angle
0被反射到单位向量中
0 got reflected into a unit vector at
角θ和中间是
angle theta and halfway between was the
saitovirtuline就是那个
saito virtu line that's that's not
现在没关系，另一个人呢
that's okay now what about the other guy
0 1
这是01好的我可以乘以
here's 0 1 ok I multiply that can I put
01在这里，所以你只是你的眼睛
the 0 1 up here so you just your eye
乘法在哪里
does the multiplication where is the
01的结果是什么输出
result of 0 1 what's the output from
从提示适用于零正弦theta
from cue applied to zero one sine theta
减去COSTHETA右它的它的
minus cos theta right it's the it's the
第二列，那就是那个
second column and so where is that
好吧，它与那个人垂直
well it's perpendicular to that guy
这是正确的我正确的，是知道
that's right I know right that was the
指出两列是
point that the two columns are
垂直，所以它必须下降
perpendicular so it's so it must go down
这样的权利正弦余弦THETAtheta和
this way right sine theta cos theta and
它并没有改变所有这些长度
it doesn't change lengths all these
我们刚刚学到的事实是关键所在
facts that we just learned are key so
有一个是零，它去了
there's there's zero one and it goes to
这家伙是什么那第二
this guy which is whatever that second
列是正弦theta减去costheta和
column is sine theta minus cos theta and
如果你检查它实际上像普通的
if you check that actually like plain
几何我相信从未发生过
geometry I believe never occurred to me
之前，但我相信这一点
before but I believe it that that this
那个角度下降到那里
angle going down to there that that goes
直通，中途
straight through and that the halfway
一个是那条线是的，我认为
one is that line yeah I think that
图片得到它，我认为它在
picture is got it and I think it's in
这个音符就是一个反射矩阵
the note so that's a reflection matrix
那是一个二乘二的反思
well that's a two-by-two reflection
你希望看到其他的矩阵吗？
matrix would you like to see some other
像这样的矩阵但是更大
matrices like this one but but larger
他们以一个名叫的人命名
they're named after a guy named
住户所以这些都是户主
householder so these are householder
反思我在做什么我在这里
reflections what am I doing here I'm
收集一些正交
collecting together some orthogonal
有用且重要的矩阵
matrices that are useful and important
和住户发现了一大堆
and householder found a whole bunch of
他们和他的算法很多
them and and his algorithm is a much
数值线性代数的用过那一部分，从而
used part of numerical linear algebra so
他从一个单位向量开始
he started with a unit vector start with
单位向量
a unit vector
你将你的转置等于1，那么它的长度
you transpose u equal 1 so the length of
向量是1，然后他创建
the vector is 1 and then he created
让我把它命名为他创造的他
let's name it after him H he created
这个矩阵的身份减2uu
this matrix the identity minus 2 uu
转置，我相信这是一个
transpose and I believe that that's a
非常有用的矩阵所以就像我一样
really useful matrix so it's just like I
认为这篇评论就像是超越了
think this review is like going beyond
1806进入什么是真正的
1806 into what is what ones are really
值得知道，值得了解
worth knowing that worth knowing
单独确定我们可以检查一下
individually ok could we just check what
是持有人的财产
are the properties of house holders
我的反思-对你而言
reflection of that I - to you you
在这里识别列时间如此
recognize here column times a row so
这是一个矩阵，是什么样的
that's a matrix and what kind of what
你能告诉我有关矩阵UU
could you tell me about that matrix u u
转移它是啊所以呃或什么
transpose it's yeah so uh or what what
我们可以谈谈关于H的事情吗？
can we say about about about H so I
我猜我相信H是一个
guess I'm believing that H is a
正交矩阵否则就不会
orthogonal matrix otherwise it wouldn't
今天在这里
be here today
所以我相信，那不仅是
so I believe that and that not only is
它正交它也有一个看
it orthogonal it is also have a look at
它对称它也是对称的
it symmetric it's also symmetric the
身份对称的uu转置是
identity symmetric uu transpose is
对称的，因此，这是一个家庭
symmetric so that this is a family of
对称正交矩阵和那个
symmetric orthogonal matrices and that
是其中一个是对称的
was one of them that's a symmetric
正交矩阵这些矩阵是
orthogonal matrix these matrices are
真的很高兴你喜欢进去
really great to have you just like in in
使用线性代数，你得到一个
using linear algebra it's you just get a
有用的矩阵的集合，您
collection of useful matrices that you
可以调用这些肯定是一个
can call on and these are definitely one
家庭，它显然是对称的
family well it's obviously symmetric
我们应该检查它是否正交
shall we check that it's orthogonal so
检查它是否正交我就是这样
to check that it's orthogonal I just so
我要检查H转置H是什么
I'm going to check that H transpose H is
这个身份我可以检查一下
the identity can I just check that
H转置与H相同
well H transpose is the same as H
因为它是对称的所以我会
because it was symmetric so I'm gonna
这个家伙，这真的是H次H
square this guy this is really H times H
我正在调整它，如果我，我会得到什么
I'm squaring it and what do I get if I
广场所以我得到了我希望我得到了
square so so I get I hope I get the
身份，但让我们看看它得到了什么
identity but let's see it what do I get
当我加上这个时，这就变得很少了
when I Square this get little multiply
出来
it out
所以，我是我，然后我得到一些
so I times I is I and then I get some
uu的数量转置这个有多少
number of uu transpose this how many do
我从那里得到了所以我正在摆平
I get for that from that so I'm squaring
这件事因为H转置H是
this thing because H transpose H is the
同样以H倍h后，我现蕾这么
same as H times H so I'm squaring it so
有多少我要放在这里谢谢
how many what do I put here for thanks
而现在我已经把这个家伙搞平了
and now I've got this guy squared with a
加上这样四个uu转置uu
plus so that's four uu transpose uu
颠倒
transpose
是的，我完全意识到我
yeah I'm totally realizing I've
一辈子练习这些
practiced for a lifetime doing these
很少的计算，但他们是
dinky little calculations but they are
晕，你会得到它的悬念
dinky and you'll get the hang of it
我现在很快就希望得到什么
quickly now what am i hoping out of that
底线是我希望你能得到的
bottom line that it is I hope you to get
我知道我是，我们是谁看到了如何
I do we get I yes we're who sees how to
从那件事情中醒来，是的
get eye out of that thing yeah u
在这里转置你是一个数字
transpose u in here is a number that was
你是列时间行的时间
you that was column times row times
列时间排，我看着
column times row and I look at the in
这里的中间是Rho时间列和
the middle here is Rho times column and
这是第一，因为它是
that's the number one right because it's
那就是那个，然后我有
there so that's one and then I have
减去其中的四个加上四个
minus four of that plus four of that
他们互相取消，我就是这样
they cancel each other and I get I so
这些是我们将使用的好矩阵
those are good matrices we'll we'll use
他们实际上他们会使用它们
them we'll use them actually they're
比克施密特好，所以我们会用
better than gram-schmidt so we'll use
他们在使事物正交
them in in making things orthogonal
那么什么是其他正交矩阵
so what what other orthogonal matrices
让我们创造一些你知道的创造
let's create some you know creating
你知道Gordo正交矩阵
Gordo orthogonal matrices is you know
这是付出总有回报，让我们觉得这样有
it's it pays off let's think so there's
一个以这个法国人命名的家庭
a family named after this French guy who
活到一百岁他是一个真正的老人
lived to a hundred he was a real old
计时器
timer
麻省理工学院有一名数学教师
well MIT had a faculty member in math
当我来到教授罢工的时候
when I came professor strike who lived
到了一百零六，我听到了他的声音
to a hundred and six and I heard him
在布朗大学做演讲
give a lecture at Brown University at
100岁，这就像是完美的你
age 100 and it was like perfect you
不能做的更好，所以他是我的
could not have done it better so he's my
灵感我继续前进我只有
inspiration I'm keep going I only have
再多10年才能到达那里
like 10 more years to get there well
这是太多反正没事亚当重新所有
it's too many anyway okay Adam re all
对
right
所以他创作的亚当艺术很好
so Adam art he created well that's the
最简单的是现在最小的下一个人
simplest the smallest now the next guy
我会去四点四
is gonna be four by four I'm going to
把它放在我看到的那个我要去的地方
put that so where I see a one I'm gonna
把Adamartis111减去1111减去
put Adam artis 1 1 1 minus 1 1 1 1 minus
1然后当我看到减去我要去的时候
1 and then when I see a minus I'm gonna
把它放在一个减号
put it in with a minus
你看到那张照片是一张照片
you saw that picture it was a picture of
H2H2h2和负H2就是这样
H 2 H 2 h 2 and minus H 2 that's what
我到了那里，我相信那些
I've got there and I believe those
列是正交的，现在是什么
columns are orthogonal right now what
我可以吗
could I do
好吧，它不是一个正交矩阵
well it's not quite an orthogonal matrix
我该怎么办才能做到这一点
what do I have to do to make this isn't
什么是相当正交的矩阵
quite an orthogonal matrix either what
我该怎么做才能使这个正交
what do I do to make that an orthogonal
矩阵/
matrix /
两个平方根我需要我需要单位
square root of two I need I need unit
矢量那里和那里的长度是
vectors there and here those lengths are
1平方1平方4平方根4
1 squared 1 squared 4 square root of 4
是2所以我最好除以2那里
is 2 so I better divided by the 2 there
而现在我在这里，我会在这里
and now here I'm gonna here I'm up to
是的，那就是那个人不告诉我
yeah so that was that one don't tell me
接下来一起来那是什么将是
the next one up what's that going to be
8比8是什么，所以这就是H4
8 by 8 what's that so this is H 4 here
哎呀4告诉我应该做些什么48
oops 4 so tell me what I should do 4 8
到8，你会觉得这很简单
by 8 you'll think this is like simple
但这是一件好事
but that's that's a good thing to say
关于它，你知道他们正在编码
about it you know they're in encoding
理论你想要的各种各样的地方
theory all sorts of places you want
一个和一个的矩阵
matrices of ones and minus ones
好吧什么是H8我要用它来构建它
ok what's H 8 I'm gonna build it out of
H4所以我会怎么样
H 4 so what am I gonna what's it going
是我要把一个H的有什么
to be I'm gonna put an H for there what
我要把另外的H4放在这里
am I going to put here another H 4 and
在这里另一个H4，最后在这里
up here another H 4 and finally here
减去H和我想我已经得到了正交
minus H and I think I've got orthogonal
列再次正确因为
columns again right because the the
这些点产品中的列与
columns within these dot products with
他们自己给0和0点产品
themselves give 0 and 0 the dot products
从这些列和这些列
from these columns and these columns
显然有减号和点
obviously have the minus and the dot
这里的产品或0和0
products in here or 0 from that and 0
从那以后它是有效的，我们可以
from that yeah it works and we could
继续到16和32和64然后
keep going to 16 and 32 and 64 but then
关于H12是什么问题
up comes a question what about H 12 is
那里有一个减去矩阵的大小
there ones and minus ones matrix of size
1212乘12
12 12 by 12 it
它并非直接来自我们的小事
it doesn't come directly from our little
每个都是大小加倍的模式
pattern which is doubling size every
时间，但你仍然可以希望和它
time but you could still hope and it
工作有一个我不知道它是什么
works there is a I don't know what it is
但有一个有那些矩阵
but there's a there's a matrix of ones
和正十二
and minus ones orthogonal twelve
正交列所以答案是肯定的
orthogonal columns so the answer is yes
好的，所以我们做了一个1806五个猜想
okay so we make an 1806 five conjecture
每个矩阵大小的每个矩阵都没有
every matrix every matrix size well not
每个矩阵大小，因为3x3不是
every matrix size because 3x3 is not
上班逐一不会
going to work one by one is not going to
工作要么是十二岁以上的作品
work either but age twelve works
h/h16我们猜想的是什么
h/h sixteen what's our conjecture we
不会是第一个猜想-就是这样
won't be the first conjecture --it that
还有那些和负者
there is a ones and minus ones
正交矩阵与正交
orthogonal matrix with orthogonal
每个尺寸的列都是如此
columns of every size n so always so so
我会开始猜测总是可能的
I'll start to conjecture always possible
if和哪个是矩阵的大小
if and which is the size of the matrix
让我们说你猜的是什么
let's say what would you guess just take
一枪你不会被要求提供证据
a shot you won't be asked for a proof
因为没有人能够证明这一点
because nobody has the proof even well
即使你可以看，你也希望如此
you could hope for even you could look
尝试六我猜是第一个
for try six I guess would be the first
那里的家伙，我不认为这是
guy there and I don't think it's
可能我认为六是不可能的
possible I think six is not possible so
每个均匀的尺寸都是我想不会的
every even sizes is I think not gonna
工作，但尝试什么是自然的想法
work but it's natural idea to try what's
接下来想到每四个的倍数
the next thought every multiple of four
如果n超过四是一个整数
if n over four is a whole number
所以，没有人有办法系统化
so but nobody has a way a systematic way
创造这些东西，就像一些
to create these things so like some of
他们是我们在这一点上我们失败了
them are we're at this point we're down
一次做一个，我们就这样做了
to doing it one at a time and we're up
到668但我们还没有那个
to 668 but we haven't got that one yet
这并不是那么疯狂所以这一切都将到来
isn't that crazy so all this is coming
来自维基百科我的简短来源
from Wikipedia my source of my short
我的老鼠在其所有的好来源
mice my source of all its good in
无论如何，数学都存在于维基百科上
mathematics is there on Wikipedia anyway
这是猜想猜想的意思
this is the conjecture conjecture means
你是否有任何该死的想法
you don't have any damn idea of whether
这是真的还是假的，每一个是
it's true or not that every is that
四分之一是的，我猜它会的
divisible by four yeah I guess it would
是600肯定是68是啊
be right 600 certainly is and 68 yeah
好的
okay
所以我认为这是第一个
so I think that's the first one that's
所以任何人，如果你找到一个大小
so anybody if if you find one of size
六，你只是跳过作业和
six six you just skip the homework and
告诉我们这个，但我不认为
tell us about that one but I don't think
我会指定他们是的我猜是的好
I'll assign them yeah I guess well yeah
我必须在网上搜索它是的
I must have searched for it online yeah
反正所以这些都是亚当的
anyway so those are the Adam are
矩阵现在我还记得其他地方
matrices now where else do I remember
正交矩阵来自井
orthogonal matrices coming from well
是的，真的是一些人的最大来源
yeah really the biggest source of some
我正在寻找正交矩阵
what I'm looking for orthogonal matrices
我正在寻找正交的基础
I'm looking for a basis of orthogonal
矢量，我们在数学上，我会去
vectors and we're in math am I going to
发现出来是向量
find vectors that come out to be
正交我们还没有看到那个
orthogonal we haven't seen that's the
笔记的下一部分，但也许你
next section of the notes but maybe you
其中被记住排序，我们将
were remembering where will we sort of
像自动显示了
like automatically show up with
他们可能是正交向量
orthogonal vectors they could be the
对称矩阵和特征向量的特征向量
eigenvectors of symmetric matrix and
那是最重要的
that's where the most important ones
来自哦，我可以告诉你
come from oh I could tell you about
虽然小波更像是小波
wavelets though wavelets are more like
这张照片是他们的减号
this picture they're ones and minus ones
或者最简单的小波就是那些
or the simplest wavelets are ones
-一旦我可以砍它之前，我去上
- once can I cut it before I go on to
在该特征向量的企业可以我
the to the eigenvector business can I
提到小波矩阵是的，这些
mention the wavelets matrices yeah these
这些都非常简单
are these are really important simple
和小波的重要结构
and important constructions so wavelets
让我是啊，让我画的这么一个画面
let me yeah let me draw a picture of so
所以我要提出四方面的方法
so I'm going to come up with four-way
我会做四个四个案例和
I'll do the four by four case and and
这是这些，这些是直角
this is these these are the orthogonal
伙计们然后下一个就是了
guys and then the next one is up and
向下和0，最后一个是0和向上
down and 0 and the last one is 0 and up
上下所以这是这对的事情，但
and down so that's that's for things but
让我告诉你矩阵所以我打电话给你
let me show you the matrix so I'll call
它是W的小波，所以我是谁
it W for wavelets so that guy I'm
以为我是1111这个人我是
thinking I was 1 1 1 1 this guy I'm
想到的是11减1减1
thinking of as 1 1 minus 1 minus 1 it's
看起来有点原子，但是
looking sort of atom hard way but but
这个家伙有1个不同之处
there's a difference here this guy is 1
减100所以小波重新缩放
minus 1 0 0 so the wavelets rescale
这就是它们之间的区别
that's that's the difference between
原子arden小波小波正在缩放
atom arden wavelets wavelets are scaling
自我缩放，最后一个人是什么
self scaling and what's the last guy
这是第四列的内容
here what's the fourth column from that
第四小波001减1是啊哈
fourth wavelet 0 0 1 minus 1 yeah so har
想到这就是哈尔
came up with that this is the haar
小波是多年前的
wavelet which was many years before the
小波词被发明，他想出了
word wavelets was invented he came up
用这种结构恐怖恐怖
with this construction the horror horror
恐怖矩阵有功能所以
the horror matrix there are functions so
他们是非常简单的功能
they're very simple functions but you
知道你可以
know you can
这使他们可以使用这是事实
that makes them usable that's the fact
他们现在很简单，我不知道
that they're so simple now I don't know
如果我们想要
if we want
看到模式是八乘八但是
see the pattern an eight-by-eight but
让我开始8x8让你知道
let me start the 8x8 so you you'll know
小波是什么，你会知道什么
what wavelets are about you'll know what
无论如何，这些恐怖小说都是有关的
these horror wavelets are about anyway
他们就是那些人
they're they're the ones that were that
我们很容易想象，所以让我们
we're kind of easy to visualize so let's
如果那是w-4让我们就这么说吧
this is if that's w-4 let's let's just
花一点时间
take a minute
它不会花很长时间，所以WH
it won't take long for WH okay so the
第一列将是八个
first column is going to be eight ones
好的
okay
什么是下一栏将是四个
and what's the next column gonna be four
一个和四个减去像这样四个
ones and four minus ones like so so four
一个和四个减去
ones and four minus ones
好的，现在是下一个颜色---
okay and now the next color - ones - -
1和0减去1减1
ones and zeros right 1 1 minus 1 minus 1
0和第四个将是零和
and 0 and the fourth will be zeros and
两个月两个月我们得到了一半
two ones and two months we got half a
矩阵现在，如果我们只是告诉我
matrix now now if we just tell me the
第五，我觉得你是怎么回事
fifth I'm what do you think what do I
放在第五个，所以它会再次
put in the fifth one so again it's gonna
挤压和重新缩放，这是什么
squeeze down and rescale and what's the
第五栏就在这里
fifth column up here that's gonna be
现在如此，减去零和零
ones and minus ones and zeros now so
它不在AMARG
it's not at AMARG
这很难，我应该怎么做
it's har and what should I put 1 1 how
他们从1101开始，然后是
they start with 1 101 my yeah and then
所有那些零哦是的，谢谢完美1
all those zeros oh yeah thanks perfect 1
减去1然后它们全部为零
minus 1 and they're all zeros and then
接下来的三栏说我们会有
the next three column says we'll have
这里1减1，减1减1
the 1 minus 1 here and the 1 minus 1
这里和1减1在这里，我看到了
here and the 1 minus 1 here and I saw
零，所以你看到它的模式
zeros yeah so you see the pattern it's
每一步都要缩放
scaling at every step
并与使矩阵具有
and and the so that matrix has the
优势是相当稀疏的排序
advantage of being quite sparse sort of
这在我的脑海里是一个或者是为了
this this in my mind is a or but for
那些参与喜欢的人
ones that's involved with like taking
平均然后这个家伙就像服用
the average then this guy is like taking
差异之间的差异
the differences differences between
那些和那些然后这就像
those and those and then this is like
以较小的规模取得差异
taking the difference at a smaller scale
我也不是那么小
I'm not also at a smaller scale so
这就是我们一直在做的事耶。是的
that's what we keep doing yeah yeah
所以这个小波看起来很简单
so that's wavelets it looks so simple
对，但只在一分钟
right but at the just a one minute
小波的历史苏哈尔发明了这一点
history of wavelet Sohar invented this
在1910年，我的意思是永远，但是
in like 1910 I mean along forever but
那么你想这是一个小波
then you wanted wavelets that were a
好一点，而不只是一些和
little better and not just ones and
减去零和零
minus ones and zeros and it that took
有些人经常思考很多
some some a lot of thinking a lot of
人们正在寻找它和英格丽德
people were searching for it and Ingrid
土桥
dobashi
所以我只会把她的名字变得出名
so I'll just put her name became famous
为了在1988年左右找到它们
for finding them so in about 1988 she
发现了很多小波的家庭和
found a lot of families of wavelets and
当我说小波时，她发现了一个整体
when I say wavelets she found a whole
很多正交矩阵
lot of orthogonal matrices that were
那个有很好的属性，所以那就是
that had good properties yep so that's
这就是现在好的照片浪潮
that's the wave of a picture okay now to
今天关闭，并与下一个连接
close today and to connect with the next
关于特征值特征向量的讲座
lecture on eigenvalues eigenvectors
正定矩阵我们真的
positive definite matrices we're really
让事物的心脏在这里
getting to the heart of things here
让我讲述这个想法
let me follow through on that idea
所以对称矩阵的特征向量
so the eigenvectors of symmetric matrix
而且正交矩阵也是
but also of an orthogonal matrix are
正交，这是真的在哪里
orthogonal and that is really where
你可以发明的人，因为你
people where you can invent because you
你不必努力工作就能找到一个
don't have to work hard you just find a
对称矩阵的特征向量
symmetric matrix its eigenvectors are
自动正交一点不
automatically orthogonal that doesn't
意味着它们非常适合使用，但有些
mean they're great for for use but some
其中非常重要
of them are really important and that
可能是最重要的是
may be the most important of all is the
傅丽叶所以你可能已经看过了
fourier so you probably have seen
傅立叶系列正弦和余弦
Fourier series sines and cosines those
伙计们是正交函数但是
guys are orthogonal functions but
离散傅立叶级数是什么
discrete Fourier series is what
每个人都在计算，而那些是
everybody computes and those are
正交向量所以正交
orthogonal vectors so the orthogonal
进入离散的矢量
vectors that go into the discrete
傅里叶变换，然后他们是
Fourier transform and and then they're
由快速傅立叶高速完成
done at high speed by the fast Fourier
转变
transform
那些是q特征向量的特征向量
those are eigenvectors of q eigenvectors
正确的q所以让我发明一下
of the right q so let me just invent the
对，告诉你正确的q得到
right tell you the right q that get
其特征向量所以，所以我在这里我们去
whose eigenvectors so so i here we go
我可以Q的载体让我你会
I can vectors of Q let me you will just
惊讶于这个矩阵是多么简单
be amazed by how simple this matrix is
它只是那个矩阵，它被称为a
it's just that matrix it's a called a
排列矩阵它只是把它
permutation matrix it just puts the
那些是傅立叶的四个八
those are the four eight for Fourier
离散离散让我说出自己的意思
discrete discrete let me put their word
离散这里转移
discrete up here transfer
所以我真的打算放弃
so I really meant to put discrete
傅里叶变换是的
Fourier transform yeah
该矩阵的特征向量首先是
the eigenvectors of that matrix first of
它们都是正交的，然后是第二个
all they are orthogonal and then second
而且更重要的是他们是
and more important they're they're
他们是非常有用的
tremendously useful they're the they're
你知道的信号处理的核心
the heart of signal processing you know
他们只是采取信号处理
in in signal processing they just take
a的离散傅立叶变换
the discrete Fourier transform of a
矢量之前他们甚至看着它我
vector before they even look at it I
意味着它就像是看待它的方式
mean it's like that's the way to see it
把它分成它的频率和
is split it into its frequencies and
那就是这个特征向量
that's what the eigenvectors of this
我们会这样做的
will do so we're going to see the
离散傅里叶变换，但我的
discrete Fourier transform and but my
这里要指出的是，他们是
point here is to know that they're
正交刚刚出来了
orthogonal is just comes out of this
事实是，特征向量
fact that the eigenvectors are
对于任何Q都是正交的
orthogonal for any Q and that is
肯定是Q每个人都可以看到
certainly a Q everybody can see that
这些列与列正交
those columns are orthogonal the columns
作为排列矩阵的印刷品
of a print that's a permutation matrix
对，这是你已经采取的列
right it's a you've taken the columns of
完全的身份
the identity which are totally
正交，你只需将它们放入
orthogonal and you just put them in a
不同的顺序，所以一个排列矩阵
different order so a permutation matrix
是对单位矩阵的重新排序
is a reordering of the identity matrix
它必须是一个q，因此它
it's got to be a q and therefore its
特征向量是正交的，它们是正交的
eigenvectors are orthogonal and they're
只是赢家我的意思是
just the winners i mean that the the
与傅立叶矩阵的矩阵
matrix of the fourier matrix with those
我将告诉你四个特征向量
four eigen vectors in it I'll show you
现在没关系，所以这真的是我们
now okay so this is really we're
今天通过领先进入完成
finishing today by leading into
星期三
Wednesday
我可以向量和特征值和我们
I can vectors and eigen values and we
碰巧正在做本征向量和
happen to be doing eigen vectors and
队列的特征值不是今天的
eigen values of a queue not today of an
在大多数情况下，它是对称的
S well most of the time it's a symmetric
我们采用的特征向量矩阵
matrix whose eigenvectors we take but
这里碰巧是我可以展示的aq
here that happens to be a q can I show
你是特征向量
you the eigenvectors
的，现在哦四个特征向量
the four eigenvectors of that now oh the
复数我会进来的
complex number I is going to come in you
你必须让它在这里，是的
have to you have to let it in here yeah
抱歉，如果s是真正对称的s
sorry ma if s if s is a real symmetric
矩阵的特征向量是真实的，但如果
matrix its eigenvectors are real but if
q是一个正交矩阵
q is a orthogonal matrix its
特征向量，即使你知道
eigenvectors even though it's you know
你不能要求更真实的矩阵
you couldn't ask for a more real matrix
比那个，但它的特征向量是
than that but its eigenvectors are at
至少一个耶的好方法是
least yeah the one the good way are
复数，所以我可以告诉你
complex numbers so can I show you the
整体上的特征向量
eigenvectors of so again overall the
今天的观点是看正交
point today is to see orthogonal
矩阵所以我现在就重复一遍
matrices so I'll just repeat now while I
能够
can
旋转这里反射小波
rotations here reflections wavelets the
家庭主人对大思考的看法
householder idea of reflections of big
具有这种形式的大型矩阵I.
large matrices that have this form I
减去2uu转置正交现在
minus 2 uu transpose orthogonal and now
我们将会看到大家伙
we're going to see the big guys the the
q的特征向量是的哦是的我们
eigenvectors of q right yes oh yeah we
我们没有正确的正交法
don't have orthonormal that's right we
没有正交我更好的划分
don't have orthonormal I better divide
通过8的平方根哦是啊所以
by square root of 8 right oh yeah so
你是对的，我以为我会得到
you're right sorry I thought I'd get
远离那个，但我没有，所以
away with that but I didn't yeah so
这些家伙是8的螺丝所以这些
these guys are screws of 8 so are these
但是这些家伙是4个人的成果
but these guys are fruits of 4 and these
伙计们很擅长-绝对地谢谢你
guys are screw to - thank you absolutely
对，是的，是的
right absolutely yeah
好吧那么什么是a的特征向量
okay so what are the eigenvectors of a
这将是一种排列
of a permutation this is going to be
很高兴看到，我将使用矩阵F.
nice to see and I'll use the matrix F
对于那的特征向量矩阵
for the eigenvector matrix of that of
那个队列那个，F代表
that of that queue up there and F is for
对你来说，它是四乘四的
for you and it be the four by four for a
矩阵好吧什么是特征向量
matrix okay what are the eigenvectors of
Q好吧所以Q是一种排列，就像我一样
Q okay so Q is a permutation so like I'm
要问你的一个特征向量
gonna ask you for one eigenvector of
每个排列矩阵什么的
every permutation matrix what what
矢量你能告诉我它实际上
vector can you tell me that it actually
特征值将是一个向量
the eigenvalue will be one what vector
你能告诉我，如果我置换它我会在哪里
can you tell me where if i permute it I
不要一一改变它
don't change it one one one one it's
喜欢它的无处不在这里一个一个一个
like it's everywhere here one one one
一，这就是零频率傅立叶
one so that's the zero frequency Fourier
向量
vector
每个人都是恒定的向量
the constant vector all ones everybody
看到如果我乘以Q它
sees that if I I multiply by Q it
不会改变现在下一个
doesn't change okay now the next one
我会告诉你现在的下一个
I'll show you the for now the next one
将是一个II平方，我立方
will be one I I squared and I cubed
当然我平方我不知道怎么回事
of course I squared I don't know how
很多当然6j人都在这
many course 6j people are in this
观众但这是我们的数学建筑
audience but this is a math building we
支付它，它是190，它是我在
pay for it it's to 190 and it's I in
这个房间是的
this room yeah
所以无论如何我是第一封信
so anyway I is the first letter in in
什么想象的，先谢谢你
what imaginary thank you the first
想象中的字母你不能说
letter in imaginary you can't say
想象中所以这样就可以了
imaginary so so so that's it okay and
那么下一个是一个我我的平方
then the next one is one I squared I
第四，我六，下一个是我
fourth I six and the next one is one I
立方体我六个i-9
cubed I six an i-9
那不仅仅是美丽和你
that's isn't that just beautiful and you
可以
could
表明这四个中的每一个
show that every one of those four
列，如果你乘以Q你
columns if you multiply them by Q you
会得到特征值，你会的
would get the eigenvalues and you would
看到它是一个特征向量，这是
see that it's an eigenvector and this is
就像一个离散的傅立叶
just sort of like a discrete fourier
东西，你知道而不是我
stuff and you know instead of e to the I
II到IXe到2iXe到3IX
II to the IX e to the 2i X e to the 3 IX
等等，我们只有矢量，但我也是
and so on we just have vectors but I so
那些是四个特征向量
those are the four eigenvectors of the
那种排列的那些和那些
of that of that permutation and those
是正交的，因为我只是检查一下
are orthogonal because I just check that
你怎么知道这第一栏
how do you know that this first column
在第二口井我应该说
in the second well I should really say
如果我是的话，第0列和第1列
0th column and first column if I'm if
我说的频率你看到了吗？
I'm talking frequencies do you see that
与那个井正交的Y是一个
that's orthogonal to that well Y is one
再加上我加上我的平方加上我的立方体相等
plus I plus I squared plus I cube equal
零是这是点积
zero that's the dot product this is
第1列点列2是的，是的，你是
column 1 dot column 2 yeah yeah you're
对
right
这恰好出来0是对的
this happens to come out 0 is that right
那个会出来0但是有人
that'll come out 0 but somebody
提到这是不对的
mentioned that this isn't right this is
我的意思是说出来了
I mean that it's true that that came out
0但是当我有虚构的向量时
0 but when I have imaginary vector
想象中的数字如此随处可见
imaginary numbers so anywhere around
这不是正确的点积
this isn't the correct dot product to
如果我有想象的话，测试正交
test orthogonal if I have imaginary
如果我有复杂的复杂载体
complex vectors if I have complex
数字复杂的向量我应该测试
numbers complex vectors I should test
第1列共轭点2列
column 1 conjugate dotted with column 2
第一栏我很好地结合了
column I conjugate well let me take
C列我应该选择哪一个
column C what which one shall I take
也许那个家伙很多人
maybe that guy in that guy many of them
你好运，但我真的
you luck out here but but really I
应该是
should be
考虑其共轭那么那么那么这些
taking their conjugate so so so these
但事情就是国家了
ones but the thing is the country the
一个复共轭是一个这样的
complex conjugate of one is one so that
那是好的，但总的来说，如果我
was that was okay but in general if I
想把第二列点缀起来
wanted to take column two dotted with
专栏我不知道可能会有四个
column I don't know maybe four would be
有点狡猾的样子看起来很棒
a little dodgy yeah look look what
发生
happens
把那一列和那一列拿走
take that column and that column take
他们积做了错误的方式使
their dot product do it the wrong way so
什么是错误的方式
what's the wrong way
忘记复杂的共轭和
forget about the complex conjugate and
按照常规方式这样做一次
just do it the usual way so one times
一个是我一次我立方体是1我平方
one is one I times I cube is 1 I squared
我六岁就是一个我得到所有的人
times I six is one I'm getting all ones
我没有在那里获得正交性
I'm not getting a orthogonality there
那是因为我忘记了我
and that's because I forgot that I
应该很好地采用复共轭
should take the complex conjugate well
这些家伙之一，我应该负我
of these guys one I should take minus I
减去我的方形减去我的确这是真的
minus I square minus i well that's real
所以没关系-他们真是太消极了
so it's okay - they're so so minus I
平方仍然减去一，所以现在如果我
squared is still minus one so now if I
这样做是零，所以让我
do it it comes out zero so so let me
再说一遍，让我这样做吧
repeat again let me just make this
声明如果Q转置Q是I和QX
statement if Q transpose Q is I and Q X
是lambdaX，QY是不同的本征
is lambda X and Q Y is a different eigen
价值Y好吧所以我正在设置
value Y okay so I'm I'm setting up the
在最后一分钟，我是主要的事实
main fact that in the last minute I'm
要记下来，所以我有一个
just gonna write down so I have an
正交矩阵我有一个特征向量
orthogonal matrix I have an eigenvector
与特征值lambda我有另一个
with eigenvalue lambda I have another
具有不同特征值的特征向量
eigenvector with a different eigen value
亩，则要求是什么
mu then the claim is that what is the
声称关于特征向量所以这里
claim about the eigenvectors so here's
有一个本征，它有一个特征值
has one eigen this has an eigen value
这具有不同的特征值
this has a different eigen value
我需要他们不同的真
I need them to be different to really
知道他们是XS和Y的
know that they're the XS and the Y's
不能是一样的那么我是什么
can't be the same so what is it that I
希望表明XI必须这样做
want to show yes that X I have to
记得这样做X转置Y是0
remember to do that X transpose Y is 0
这是正交性的
that's orthogonality that's
我有复杂载体的正交性
orthogonality for complex vectors I have
要记住要改变每一个
to remember to take the to change every
我在载体之一和负我
I to a minus I in one of the vectors and
我可以通过玩耍证明这一事实
I can prove that fact by playing with
这些都是通过开始玩
these these by playing with starting
从这里我可以得到那就好了
from here I can get to that ok that's it
我们今天做了很多很多事情
we've done a lot today a lot of stuff
关于正交矩阵的重要矩阵
about orthogonal matrices important ones
和我重要的来源
and the sources of important ones I ghen
vectors and so it'll be eigenvectors on
矢量，所以它将是特征向量
星期三
Wednesday